well that didn't sound very good at
least i'm making progress in there you
guys
nope i'm not going to show you what's
behind the wall and welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft we are
very very busy at the moment doing lots
of little projects including the one
behind this
wall and it is officially going to be
called project dirt house but i haven't
actually told mumbo that it's called
project dirt house because
i don't have a way of telling him other
than going and putting down signs in his
base so i had the idea of an instant
messaging system
and that's what we've been working on
actually so as you can see i've got this
sort of tube here and we're actually
going to continue this all the way under
water and it works very similarly to the
way that his item sorter works
it's going to propel an item using water
all the way along actually i might need
to change this bottom bit to ice i just
realized i need to figure out how this
works before i start building this stuff
and then it's going to arrive at mumbo's
base i think that the chunks have to be
loaded
but i am officially out of glass so
we're going to go and use mumbo smelter
oh
what do you think you know what what's
going on here you can't just have a
party up there what is this so we're
here at mumbo's base and you can see
that i've actually started the little
chill maybe you can't see it at all
no look there it is you can see that
there's a tube right here and this is
what i've been working on i believe
that i have to change this to ice for it
to work
but we'll see so let's go and see how
mumbo's item sorter works first yeah
he's got ice on the bottom of his so
we're probably gonna need that
essentially it's gonna do exactly what
this does here you see how it this item
travels all the way along really
[Music]
i might just clogged up the system
uh
no there we go there we go
there's the remnants of last episode in
that one i wonder if he's got rid of all
the chickens yet
it doesn't seem that he you need ice
everywhere you only need ice underneath
the sign i'm glad that i came and
checked this out before i did anything
so this obviously keeps the momentum
going and this is how the message system
is gonna work essentially what we're
gonna do
is i'm going to throw an item in at my
end i'm going to try again it's going to
travel in
now how is that supposed to go around
mumbo
have you tested your own thing
your item your item thing doesn't work
it just stops
so at my end of the messaging system i'm
going to throw in my piece of paper with
the message in it's going to travel all
the way to mumbo's base like that and
then it's going to get inside a hopper
and then it's going to activate a bit of
redstone it's going to go ding ding ding
ding no he clearly hasn't gotten rid of
all of the chickens yet and he's going
to get
a message from me and it's going to be
really cool because it'll be well it'd
be like texting each other in games so
we can have private conversations
without everyone else on the server
looking in on what we're doing
so that's what we're going to be doing
today but that's not all i've been doing
i've been extremely busy as you know it
is phantom hunting season and
i decided to be a late entry to the race
now i had like 40 phantom kills to my
name
and i decided to go and spend a couple
of nights hunting them a couple of
nights turned into a few nights
a few nights turned into dozens of
nights and now i have
319 phantom kills
but i'm still only halfway
to what cub fans at 623
phantoms
i'm not sure i have the energy
the resilience to do
that many
phantom kills i just don't think i've
got it in me
if you want me to go for it do let me
know but i'm a little bit scared mumbo
did tell me how this worked do i put the
items in in here
oh please don't tell me i've put them in
the wrong part i feel like i've just
please tell me i haven't broken the
system
is that the fuel
that might be the fuel
how does this work where's the input i
should be able to use a smelter
let's try this one
does this start smelting things he told
me where to put the items in i just i've
broken it i've
wait but look this goes down oh there we
go
okay
magic happened all right i'm not gonna
question it so this is definitely input
and it's going fast
the wonders of redstone everybody thank
goodness that we're a bit of a team
because
this i i didn't even know where to put
the sand let's be honest
there's no chance of me making one of
these
i wonder how long it's gonna take to get
through all of this
it has already done quite a lot why is
mumbo got his eye trade pass
in his smelter
if mumbo's lost his pass someone please
tell him he he's left it in the super
smelter
what on earth
this is the this is the minecraft
equivalent of losing your phone down the
toilet in my opinion
what is this doing here
i don't know why that's made me laugh so
much
it's so typical mumbo honestly anyway
let's head back to the base because
that's not all i've been working on
apart from killing many many phantoms
night on night i do feel sorry for joe
he's only killed zero
oh i've actually finished this third
layer now i have been toying with this
layer for
many days now
i have edited the height several times
and it's very very time consuming from
this angle
it looks just about right
from the bottom though
it looks a little bit stubby it could
easily be a bit taller but because i
want to add a fourth layer that won't it
won't look like any of them it will look
like sort of the topping off of it all
i need a bit more space so i've made
this one here just a few blocks stubbier
so that i can fit in the finale piece up
here but that does mean that this
episode the eye of sauron will have to
go because i i mean it didn't really
last long i'm afraid but
i really have to work on this area
because my base is really quite coming
along fast and thank goodness this goes
really quick i'm sorry iskal
it's it's been good um i mean it's only
it's only been like an episode that this
has survived
but it's gotta go gotta make way for the
real work here it's taking too long to
do it while crouching so i'm just doing
hot coals
out
oh no no no no no phantoms yes
come to me my pretties oh man they're
all the way up there
guys i'm guys i'm down here please don't
make me go oh see i'm out of range for
them they don't know where i am right
now so i'm gonna have to go to get them
see if we can get one in mid air oh no
they've seen me
no bad timing bad timing bad timing
ow how this is no this is not good
oh
no way
okay well that was surprisingly easy i
just accidentally used my last rockets
oh
oh great here we go again
you know
i cannot sleep because i need to hunt
the phantoms but the phantoms are
hunting me when i'm trying to do
something pretty delicate also you might
notice this little puff of smoke in the
air it's rather close to my base
but that
is a shop believe it or not and it's not
even look look at this look at this guys
this isn't even in the shopping district
this is straight up in my area
although i haven't really laid claim to
this entire thing right let's give tango
some more of my money
as if he's not had enough of it oh
on top of that
what's going on here
there wasn't a mask on this before
and what's happened to the tour
wait that's the uh the is that the
convex thing that their little symbol
cause cub fans got like a vex thing on
him oh i i've suddenly understood the
meaning of the convex
right
right i i get it what else have they
done also this is a fantastic looking
building properly looks like a factory i
am in love with this style and impressed
with how much
bricks there are how many bricks there
are in this what else have they done no
they haven't they've completely
halloweened up the place
look at my pickle i mean to be fair i
didn't even build this so i can't be mad
look at the horns on that thing
crazy cool they've obviously put a bit
of time into this let's check our money
as well has we made any sales oh a
couple of sales that money will be
directly invested into my firework
habits what else have they done they've
turned mumbo mumbo spoiler shop into a
pumpkin and
they've oh what's this
they've added loads of witch's faces to
the smelter that zuma made sorry i just
butchered his name uh xei zoo
[Music]
void
yep they've definitely been up to no
good you know what strange i've never
been a big halloweeny kind of person i
kind of
celebrate it a little bit which is why i
actually have been wearing my halloween
skin for quite some time but nobody's
really noticed and i wonder why that is
this is my halloween skin well let me
take off my clothes so you can see
there we go look this is my halloween
skin it doesn't look much different
right well not quite
this is what
this is my halloween skin
hello
because the back of my head looked like
a pumpkin on its own just without all
the orange
i thought it'd be funny just to add a
little pumpkin face on the back
it is okay it's a bit it's a bit weird
over halloween skin but
it works
nothing looks like it's changed but
they're like where's your halloween skin
it's here
so when it comes to making this
messaging tube i don't really understand
too much like the redstone at either end
i mean it's pretty simple putting in a
hopper but mumbo can be in charge of
making it all bing and ding and light up
and all that kind of stuff
we can just be in charge of making the
tubes because that's our thing i'm not
too worried about covering it up because
as we can swim
i'm thinking that if i come prepared i
can build everything i need to within
this just being able to swim and even
when you run out of water if you can
actually keep just walking in it it's
actually amazing like watch as i come
out here i'm still able to walk inside
this freely and place blocks and mine
quite happily i can even just keep
swimming so as long as i have a swimming
entrance i'm not too worried about the
actual building part of this one at all
i think for the most part i'm gonna
stick with a straight line
i'm pretty sure this all has to be
equally spaced
oh dear
i didn't really think about this at all
my conduit is in there and that's what's
been giving me the night vision or the
underwater vision oh well we're gonna
have to do this the old-fashioned way i
guess
keep going up for air this is kind of
weird isn't it looking down the tube
like that
kind of looks like it's all one gigantic
tunnel i love it
if we really oh i again i'm forgetting
that i need air whoa
look at this
i'm swimming i'm swimming so fast it's
the dolphins where did they go they make
me swim fast oh whoa you can get some
serious speed
oh my goodness
okay i swear i swam all the way here now
i've got to do the long swim back okay
we're getting pretty close now well
we're basically right next to his kelp
farm and now we really need to consider
how we're going to tackle this
and then the tube will end up right here
now i don't know if that's directly in
the middle but if mumbo needs to edit it
he can change that fairly easily that's
a lot of blocks that it takes to get
there this is quite a long message
system it's got to go
all this way
it's got to turn
then left
before it eventually
get to my base
now that is a huge distance and it only
works if the chunks are loaded so if
both of us are in our base
the item should travel all the way along
fairly swiftly so i'm not too worried
about that i'm going to text mumbo so
much in this and i'm just going to send
so much random stuff that makes no sense
we're officially out of stained glass
again
but
it's coming across it's coming on quite
nicely in fact i think the next thing i
want to do is get myself some sea
pickles and light up this messaging
system
pickles pickles pickles
i'm getting flashbacks to the pickles on
the seafloor song but we're not planting
pickles on the seafloor
let's see if that's made any difference
shall we that is exactly what we needed
that looks perfect it looks really nice
however i'm thinking that sea lanterns
might be a better fit seeing as that's
what i've used to light up my base and
mumbo has also done the same i really
need to finish doing this it looks like
a banana is just floating in my base
right now i honestly get distracted so
easily i just went and did the messaging
system and i wasn't even finished doing
this
my mind sometimes
just because i'm removing this eye
doesn't mean that i'm not watching okay
i'm watching everybody on this server
all right i know what's going on mostly
sometimes maybe i'm exaggerating
we are nearly
gonna go back yeah we are back to
normality oh wow look at this
it looks it looked like my base had
spots for a second
but this space is reserved distinctly
for
my
next layer that i'm going to be making
i've got to say
for someone that's never done anything
in this style before whatsoever
i'm pretty proud of myself for how this
has come out this is
yeah this has gone really really well
this base
and i think what's really cool about it
is this is something i would never make
a normal video on i would never come up
with this and make a tutorial about how
to make a giant futuristic skyscraper
cake blender coffee machine all the
things that it's been called it's pretty
unique looking and i'd say we're
probably
60 done i'd say to give you an idea i
know it looks kind of finished even
excluding what's going to go on on the
inside
this is still got a lot to do with the
whole detailing thing we need another
layer at the top to top it off there's a
lot of stuff that needs doing now if i
had my way there may even be another
layer that goes around the outside like
a secondary ring
but that's maybe way down the line this
season is gonna hopefully last a long
enough time so i can finish this base
but
i would say that this is less of a base
to me
than a monument or it's more of a
landmark to me see this
these are builds that pickle shop is a
shop that's a house that's a cart you
wouldn't look at any of these and think
this is a landmark whereas when you come
across this
this giant base
this is a
proper landmark this really puts itself
on the map as a very distinct location
within its own right
you know that i said my base was looking
more like a a super villain layer well i
think scar might have beat me because
the inside of this volcano if this
doesn't scream hey i'm a bad dude then i
don't know what does he's living inside
of a volcano and there seems to be like
there's a walkway here but this looks
dangerous i love it scar is so talented
i mean look at this volcano so brilliant
and the amount of blocks that went into
this and then the glass on top of that
absolute insanity there appears to be
more than one spoiler wall at the moment
we won't even have a look at that we're
gonna drift straight over that one i
haven't actually had a look around the
server in a really long time i don't
really know what's going on anymore this
looks like the hermit central station
which is going to be the big monorail
line
and then we've got the shopping district
which seems to grow a new face every
single day kind of want to find cub fan
and scar and see what they're up to
maybe they're at the cubs base i've
never be i've not been to cubs base in a
really long time in fact i don't go to
this part of the the world unless i've
gotten seriously lost
or i've been tagged as far as i'm aware
this is cubs base
oh my goodness
oh my goodness what is going on well
there's the tag building
cub fans got factories upon factories of
things
oh he's right there
what's he doing why is he hitting a
button on the floor
has he even noticed me
hold on let's see
what's he expecting to happen
this is hilarious
do you think he knows we're here
no go on press it again see if something
happens
what's he doing
[Laughter]
no no no no no no no no no no no i
didn't mean it i didn't mean
i just wanted to scare you when you hit
the button
come no come no
it was an accident it was an accident it
was an accident cub
he got rid of the button i asked him
what the button did and he just got rid
of it what is he doing
this is like the most bizarre thing i i
feel like i've just come across cub and
he's like been talking to himself
nice try guy
that was some swift reactions there
i'm too good at flying now scar
[Laughter]
he's trying to hit me desperately is
there something under here that he
doesn't want me to see
let's see if this button it maybe it is
just a rock
why on earth was he putting a button on
the floor there's no redstone under here
i think cub fans just legitimately gone
a bit nuts
wait look
even though these don't give off any
light because i have optifine it gives
me a light source that's pretty cool if
only i had tnt right now
if only oh my goodness if i had tnt
night right now imagine that i could
place a bunch down he'd place down that
button again and boom
alas i do not have my farm yet i really
need to get my hands on this tnt it's
time for us to emerge i feel like i want
a tour of cubs base i've not really been
in contact with a lot of the hermits on
the far side of the island i kind of
want to know what's going on i've been
focusing so much on my base recently
i've i've forgotten to stop and smell
the roses or smell cubs base
now where did those two run off to oh
there he is
is that a boat no what's he up to
i feel like i just want to watch him
again see what see what things he does
you see can you see me peeping through
here
what is cub fan doing
what is it with him and the buttons
this is so weird
there's like a conspiracy theory going
on or something i have no idea what's
going on anymore this is what i'm
dealing with on the server you guys
just absolute madness
i bet i bet on cubs video this makes a
whole lot of sense
i'm stealing his phantoms this is the
only way i'm gonna win the competition
oh wait he's been using a bow and arrow
i am not that smart you see i've just
been using the axe i haven't been flying
to get them i've just been waiting for
them to come to me and then bopping them
on the head with the axe but if i was
smart i'd use something like the bow and
arrow
this is where i've been doing my phantom
hunting
oh he slept but there's still one up
there i'm going for it
where are we did i
i got it
do you have any idea how hard that is
when you're flying oh my goodness
well i've got 327 he's got 633
that's not gonna be that good
i've got a long way to go if i even want
to compete and i'm still debating
whether i even want to compete because
300 phantoms is the equivalent of like i
don't know 16 hours grinding phantoms
maybe it's a really long time night only
comes around so every so often and then
you get this kind of thing where people
sleep and then it skips today and you
miss your chance all together so as you
can see we've got quite a lot to do
still i need to finish up these tubes
and make sure that they're linked up to
mumbo's base so that we can make this
instant messaging system i think i am
going to pursue the phantom run but
zombie cleo's online she's got
635 kills that's a huge amount the other
thing is i don't know whether to put
these tubes because i obviously need one
tube that goes to my base and one tube
that goes to mumbos because otherwise we
can't wait well the water has to flow in
one direction so i'm not entirely sure
whether to make the tubes go side to
side or one above the other mumbo said
he doesn't really mind and i guess i
don't really mind either oh these things
kelp really get in the way explain that
to me everyone how does that work so i
went through here right click that it
should have ended up on this side but
somehow it ended up on this side of the
kelp that makes an oh
air
humans need to breathe
if we go over this way through the
nether we can actually go and see the
phantom run prizes so we'll see if it's
worth the time investment
there it is
that is the phantom monument this is the
whole
this is the thing where it's actually
really well made zuma did a really good
job he's very good at replicating the
things that are in game with like the
statue of the her well the statue of
hermity that was pretty good and this
actually looks really legit as well
loving the blues
so if we go over to this island we can
see
it says
for the month of october phantom hunting
season is declared the hermit who kills
the most phantom wins the contents of
this chest as time passes the chest will
fill with goodies now i don't know if i
can contribute but there's a decent
amount of stuff in here blue ice me
prismarine meh cobweb meh 64 name tags
yes
yes please
that is brilliant an elytra with mending
and unbreaking three
that's also useful one stack of each
wool from x's shop also pretty good a
netherstar conduit and 64 diamonds i
will
contribute a trident i think i don't
know if i'm allowed but i'm gonna put a
trident in there it's kind of like
betting on myself if i don't win i lose
a trident
oh and there's a giant skull that you
come out of as well
so that's pretty cool and i would like
to win but i'm like seriously behind if
i'd started this phantom hunting season
at the beginning of october i might be
in the lead but
as it stands i'm well over 300 behind
cub and
yeah it's it's going to be it's going to
be a difficult one i think so this is
where the last layer needs to happen
and i probably need to do a little bit
of experimenting first so it starts off
with a circle
i basically need to make a circle now
that's not going to touch
the towers one bit it needs to seriously
stay within the middle but anyway that's
what we're going to be working on in the
meantime between episodes and hopefully
you can see where this is going to go
it's going to have a circle within the
center of this it's going to go up and
over and then at the top there's going
to be something that's where i actually
plan on making my official nether portal
i think at this point
everybody has a
elytra so i'm thinking of moving this
portal all the way up to the very very
top of the base and then they can either
fly down or well the only thing is they
might have to use the elevator to go up
which actually gives it a really nice
purpose
and i'm hoping very shortly i can get
get on to making this mob farm because
there are still mobs spawning in here
man that takes a good 20 seconds to get
up there that actually takes a long long
time i'm not sure who owns this island
does scar on this island
or does mumbo in this island i know that
mumbo owns the chain of islands that
goes one two possibly its mumbos
i can't help but feel that this isn't
going to be used now there we go
starting again phantoms are pretty scary
so you've got to kind of occupy your
time when when you're getting rid of
them
phantom phantom bit on the head bop it
on the head bop it on the head phantom
phantom i won't go to bed killing
phantoms is a waiting game and you've
got to keep yourself occupied when you
when you're farming so we're up to 385
now i feel like i have too many projects
going on at the moment since it's the
end of the episode it's time to keep
working
on what's going on behind this wall
goodbye everyone